Preliminary Guide to the Neal E. Miller Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory
  - Audiovisual material
    - To be spliced back into remnants, 1.0 (Box 63)
      The reel title is partially illegible.
    - Winter 1953 reels 1-4, 1.0 (Box 64)
    - Winter reels 5-8, 1.0 (Box 65)
    - Winter reel 9-12, 1.0 (Box 66)
    - Animated slides for Paris Ibro talk, 1.0 (Box 67)
    - Flynn - cat aggression (4), 1.0 (Box 68)
    - Yale work plan, 1.0 (Box 69)
    - Yale Miller-Coons (edited excerpts of eating produced by brain stem which were omitted from the Miller APA (1957) Symposium address), 1.0 (Box 70)
      Label includes the following text: Included are: (1) one pellet snuffling scene, (2) one far shot of panel pushing for food and (3) three close shots of panel pushing for food, Also included are shots showing: (1) reflexive eating in cat, (2) Fear of a compartment conditioned via brain stem in a cat, (3) Demonstration of Herb Bunny's Reward-Escapes apparatus
    - Miller - record data: dub, Sony 3600, 1973; 1.0 (Box 71)
    - 3 light, 1.0 (Box 72)
    - Harlow's monkey, 1.0 (Box 73)
    - Neal Miller in conversation, 1977; 1.0 (Box 74)
    - Reaction formation - food training, 1.0 (Box 75)
      Includes pieces of paper in box.
    - React formation - reel II, 1.0 (Box 76)
    - 810, 1956 March 26–1956; 1.0 (Box 77)
    - Mind of man - Dr. Miller sequence, 1.0 (Box 78)
    - Learning and performance elicited by electric stimulation of brain (ESB), 1.0 (Box 79)
      Label includes the following text: Miller, Roberts, and Delgado Film (not spliced, do not project - remnants taped together) Prof. N. E. Miller, Rockefeller University, New York, N. Y. 10021
    - Sue Strong, Brucker - Miller: from Mysteries of the Mind (after black leader shot of Taub's monkeys), 1.0 (Box 80)
      Label includes the following text: Return to Dr. Neal E. Miller PO Box 160 Guilford, CT 06437 10 min.
    - Biofeedback and self-regulation - Neal E. Miller, 1979; 1.0 (Box 81)
    - Motivation and reward in learning, 1953 June; 1.0 (Box 82)
      Label includes the following text: First print after renovation of negative by Rapid Film Technique, Inc., 21 W. 46th St., N. Y. (slightly out of synchronization)
    - Horizon mind and body: SL 198 - 204, Professor Miller, 1.0 (Box 83)
    - Horizon mind and body: SL 198 - 204, Professor Miller, 1.0 (Box 84)
    - Motivation and reward, 1.0 (Box 85)
      The reel title is partially illegible. The label reads: Original negative voice track, narration only, without buzzer. This would be used only if narration is re-recorded. It would have to be re-synchronized with the film. This is film 3-3 of [unreadable]-Miller memo.
    - Electric stimulation of brain (ESB) - eat & gnaw, 1968; 1.0 (Box 86)
    - Electric stimulation of brain (ESB) - eat & gnaw, 1968; 1.0 (Box 87)
    - Electric stimulation of brain (ESB) - eat & gnaw, 1968; 1.0 (Box 88)
    - Electric stimulation of brain (ESB) - eat & gnaw, 1968; 1.0 (Box 89)
    - Learning motivated by electric stimulation of brain (ESB) - Miller, Roberts, and Delgado, 1.0 (Box 90)
    - Motivation and rewards in learning: rats, 1.0 (Box 91)
    - Rats: motivation and reward in learning, 1.0 (Box 92)
    - Learning effects on somatic manifestations of stress, 1978; 1.0 (Box 93)
    - Tape of lecture at Sophia University, 1.0 (Box 94)
      Recorded from a lecture at Asahi Shinbun Hall.
    - Neal Miller talk at Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), 1972; 1.0 (Box 95)
    - Science Now, 1984 June 14; 1.0 (Box 96)
    - Science Now, 1.0 (Box 97)
    - Miller BSA 1978 - evaluating BF, 1.0 (Box 98)
    - Open lecture in Kyoto, 1972 August 21; 1.0 (Box 99)
    - Behavior modification: welcome - H. Slucki; long-term impact of Dollard & Miller's wed of behavioral & psychoanalytic - N. E. Miller, 1.0 (Box 100)
    - Winter 13, 14 and discards from first preliminary assembly for new film, 1957; 1.0 (Box 101)
    - Summer remnants new 8-11, 1.0 (Box 102)
    - Sound perforated winding A, 1.0 (Box 103)
    - Sound perforated winding A, 1.0 (Box 104)
    - Motivation and reward in learning (original positive work print), 1.0 (Box 105)
      Label includes the following text: Used in timing and recording the original sound track. Of no further use except as a record of the original photography. Cannot be used for film showings. Not listed in May-Miller memo).
    - Motivation and reward in learning (fine grain positive), 1.0 (Box 106)
    - Motivation and reward in learning - "C+" normal, 1.0 (Box 107)
    - Learning motivated by electrical stimulation of the brain (magnetic not optical sound track), 1.0 (Box 108)
      Includes audio only, not optical information.
    - Motivation and reward in learning - "C" dark, 1.0 (Box 109)
    - Motivation and reward in learning, 1.0 (Box 110)
      Label includes the following text: Negative sound effects track, possibly buzzer only. Item 3-C on May-Miller memo.
    - Psychology of human relations, 1977 October 27; 1.0 (Box 111)
    - ABC News 20/20 "Depression", 1.0 (Box 112)
      Case previously included a letter dated 1985 July 1 from Julius Segal, Director of the Division of Communications and Education in the Department of Health and Human Services. See correspondence in box 40.
    - Effects of emotional stress on the immune system, 1978 March 17; 1.0 (Box 113)
    - CBS conquers brain study, 1.0 (Box 114)
    - Woiper - blood exchange chemistry entry, 1.0 (Box 115)
    - Horizon mind and body: SL 184-191, Miller's experiment, 1.0 (Box 116)
    - Horizon mind and body: SL 184-191, Miller's experiment, 1.0 (Box 117)
    - Horizon mind and body: SL 184-191, Miller's experiment, 1.0 (Box 118)
    - Horizon mind and body: SL 184-191, Miller's experiment, 1.0 (Box 119)
    - Motivation in learning (thalamus - head picture), 1.0 (Box 120)
  - Aaronson/Coons Book, 1995 (Box 47)
  - Academy of Behavioral Medicine Research -- Neal Miller Award to Clemens Kirschbaum, 1995 (Box 47)
  - Adams, David -- On Seville Statement on Violence,UNESCO [Peace Movement] {See also American Psychologist re Seville Statement}, 1986 (Box 47)
  - Adam, Gyorgy [Hungary], 1987 (Box 47)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1986 (Box 47)
  - American Association for Advancement of Science [150th anniversary - NEM's suggestions for booklet and stamp, 1994 (Box 47)
  - American Philosophical Society correspondence, 1998 (Box 47)
  - American Philosophical Society, underclass symposium [David Hamburg article], 1992 (Box 47)
  - APA Award for Joseph Brady [NEM nomination], 1991 (Box 47)
  - American Psychologist re Seville Statement on Violence, 1990 (Box 47)
  - APA Award Ceremony [NEM given citation for outstanding lifetime contribution to psychology], 1991 (Box 47)
  - APA 1992: Correspondence re NEM talk on rel. between lab and clinic, and large-print copy of talk (Box 47)
  - APA Centennial, 1991-1992 (Box 47)
  - APA - Citation for outstanding lifetime contribution to psychology, 1992 (Box 47)
  - APA - Committee on Scientific Awards [NEM nomination of A. Wagner for Distinguished Scientific Contribution + evaluations of John Liebeskind and Joseph Brady], 1990 (Box 47)
  - APA - Ethical principles for psychology, 1990 (Box 47)
  - APA - Correspondence w. Ray Fowler, CEO, 1993 (Box 47)
  - APA - SAGE program talk at convention ["How to Prepare for Totally Unexpected Opportunities"], 1991 (Box 47)
  - APA - Science Advisory Committee, 1990 (Box 47)
  - American Psychological Society - first annual convention, 1989 (Box 47)
  - Appetitive behavior - Columbia U. Seminar, 1991 (Box 47)
  - American Psychological Foundation - NEM chair of committee for Gold Medal selection in science, 1991 (Box 47)
  - Banff Lecture materials, 1985 (Box 47)
  - Banuazizi, Ali - stomach balloon in rat, 1971 (Box 47)
  - "Behavioral Influences on Endocrine and Immune Systems" -- Report of Dr. Alfred Fishman, 1989 (Box 47)
  - Behavioral Medicine lecture to European S.A. Behavioral Therapy, undated (Box 47)
  - Biobehavioral Self-Regulation and Health conference of 1991, 1990 (Box 47)
  - Biofeedback, Evaluating of clinical effectiveness, 1988 (Box 47)
  - Biofeedback -- International Congress, Japan 1993 -- Correspondence w. Hisashi Hirai, 1991 (Box 47)
  - BSA [Biofeedback Society of America] - Prospective cooperative study of behavioral treatment of headaches, 1985 (Box 47)
  - BSA Headache Study - Final materials, 1988 (Box 47)
  - BSA Headache Study - Retrospective, 1990 (Box 47)
  - BSA - Hostility toward behavioral treatments [D. Lambro and A. Roberts], 1985 (Box 47)
  - BSA Miscellaneous, 1985 (Box 47)
  - Biofeedback -- NEM intro to bk. International Perspectives on Self-Regulation, 1989 (Box 47)
  - Birbaumer, Niels - Correspondence re paper on scoliosis, 1994 (Box 47)
  - Birkhauser Boston, Inc. - correspondence re NEM chapter for Neurosciences: Paths to Discovery, 1990 (Box 47)
  - Blanchard, Edward B. - NEM recommendation for him for as Distinguished Professor at SUNY, 1988 (Box 47)
  - Booth, David A. -Correspondence, 1987 (Box 47)
  - Brain - Recording single cell - References. to Ertes-Miller, 1994 (Box 47)
  - Brines, Michael - NEM recommendation for, 1993 (Box 47)
  - Brown, Judson - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 47)
  - Bullock, Dr. Merry [Sr. Scientist, APA] -- Correspondence on work of Science Compendium, 1995 (Box 47)
  - Butler, Francine [Executive Director, AAPB - Association for Applied Psychophysiology/Biofeedback] - Correspondence, including description of NEM's accident in airport, 1995 (Box 47)
  - Carmona, Alfredo -- Correspondence, 1989 (Box 47)
  - Chestnuts and other nuts and fruit trees [NEM collection of articles]
  - Conflict articles of Seymour Epstein -- stemming from NEM's original work, and correspondence, 1985 (Box 47)
  - Congress, NEM letters to - Re NIH and funding for biomedical research, 1994 (Box 47)
  - Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station -- letters sent to members of Connecticut Appropriations Committee, to NH Register, to NY Times, etc., concerning funding and saving, esp. in 1996 and 1998, 1996, 1998 (Box 47)
  - Coons, T- NEM recommendation for student Tom Ettinger [work on Picasso], 1995 (Box 47)
  - Coons, T. - Correspondence re animal rights article, 1991 (Box 47)
  - Coons/Miller chapter contract for Exploring Psychology, 1984 (Box 47)
  - Coons, T. - General, 1958-1998 (Box 47)
  - Costa Rica [NEM letter to President of Peace University there, re achieving international peace], 1989 (Box 47)
  - Counter-conditioning project - NEM's research plan at Rockefeller U., 1984 (Box 47)
  - Cousins, Norman - Conference at Lake Arrowhead, where NEM spoke on placebo effect, 1988 (Box 47)
  - Cousins, Norman - 3-yr. report on psycho-neuroimmunology at UCLA, etc., 1989 (Box 47)
  - Cousins, Ruth [Psi Chi], 1991 (Box 47)
  - Davis, John D. [Jack] - Correspondence, work with NEM on blood exchange, articles, 1996 (Box 47)
  - Dennenberg, Victor, 1993 (Box 47)
  - Dewsbury, Donald,, 1996-97 - Correspondence re autobiography (Box 47)
  - Dienstfrey, Harris [Intent and learning], 1996 (Box 47)
  - Dollard, John - info on for Japanese dictionary, 1993 (Box 47)
  - Doob, Leonard - Correspondence and tribute, 1996 (Box 47)
  - Dworkin, Barry - General, 1987-1993 (Box 47)
  - Dworkin, Barry - Nomination for SEP and CV, 1997 (Box 47)
  - Eisenberg, Dr. Leon (Harvard), 1994 (Box 47)
  - Eckman, Paul - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 47)
  - Ellertson, Bjorn [University of Bergen], 1994 (Box 47)
  - Encyclopedia of Neroscience [NEM chapter - Geo. Adelman], 1994 (Box 47)
  - Engel, Bernard - Correspondence and recommendation, 1994 (Box 47)
  - "Fat Rat" info, 1997 (Box 47)
  - Federation of American Scientists - Correspondence w. Jeremy Stone, Pres., 1990 (Box 47)
  - Filewich, Robert - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 47)
  - Fonberg, Elzbieta [Poland], 1994 (Box 47)
  - Frankenhaeuser, Marianne [Stockholm]- general, 1996 (Box 47)
  - Frankenhaeuser, Marianne - retirement symposium, 1991 (Box 47)
  - Frustration and Aggression, 1991 (Box 47)
  - German Society of Behavioral Medicine - NEM spoke at 6th Congress, March 1997 (Box 47)
  - Glazer, Howard, 1990 (Box 47)
  - Government letters by NEM re budget cuts [including note from President Clinton], 1996 (Box 47)
  - Hamburg, David, 1996 (Box 47)
  - Handbook of Health Psychology [NEM on Advisory Board], 1993 (Box 47)
  - Hirai, Hisashi - NEM invited to give keynote address at 3rd International Congress of Biobehavioral Self-Regulation, Tokyo - Sept. 1993, 1991 (Box 47)
  - Holman, Halsted, 1992 (Box 47)
  - Hovland, Carl - biographical memoir, 1997 (Box 47)
  - Hull, Clark - NEM letter to A. Amsel, 1996 (Box 47)
  - Ince, Lawrence P., 1986 (Box 47)
  - International Society for Research and Aggression, Keynote speaker in Hungary, 1989 (Box 47)
  - International Stress Management Association [J. McGuigan], 1992 (Box 47)
  - Laskey, Jack [Julian], 1995 (Box 47)
  - Leibowitz, Sarah - NEM recommend. and papers, 1988 (Box 47)
  - Lipsitt, Lewis, 1992 (Box 47)
  - Ornish, Dean, 1992 (Box 47)
  - Recommendation, letters of, 1986-1987, 1997 (Box 47)
  - Rockefeller University -- 75th Anniversary [NEM and lab photo in article], 1976 (Box 47)
  - Rosenzweig, Mark - Drugs to improve IQ, 1984 (Box 47)
  - Schneiderman, Neil, 1987 (Box 47)
  - Scoliosis, International Device, 1992 (Box 48)
  - Scoliosis, General, 1985 (Box 48)
  - Society for Neuroscience: Brain Facts, 1992 (Box 48)
  - Society f. Neuroscience: Nov 2000 mtg. N. Orleans (Box 48)
  - Soviet Exchange, 1987 (Box 48)
  - Squire, Larry, 1994 (Box 48)
  - Talks at Pace U. and Hunter College, 1985 (Box 48)
  - Ursin, Holger - Correspondence 1994-95 (Box 48)
  - Whitehead, William - Recommendation, 1990 (Box 48)
  - Wickramasekera, Ian - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 48)
  - Wolfle, Dael - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 48)
  - Miscellaneous Videos on Brain Research, Animal Research: Interview w. Gendel, KNBC News, re Brain Stim and Pain; Mysteries of the Mind, Sue Strong Biofeedback Practical Application; Discover Series program on Motion Sickness Astronaut Training w. Pat Cowings; APA: Importance of Animal Research in Psychology; FBR [Foundation for Biomedical Research]: "Hope" - Importance of animal research, 3 families; FBR: "Caring for Life" - on laboratory animal care; NOVA: "Avoiding the Surgeon's Knife" [Dec. '91] -- Dean Ornish's Reversing Heart Disease; Soc. for Neuroscience: "Brain Research Update; Discovering Psychology #23: "Health, Mind, and Behavior"; #24: "In Space, Toward Peace"; 2 videos with no labels (Box 48)
  - Miscellaneous contemporaries of NEM: Raymond Dodge, Carl Hovland, O.H. Mowrer (record), Clark Hull (articles), B.F. Skinner (articles), Kenneth Spence (article), Visiting Professors (correspondence) (Box 48)
  - ACAR [Advisory Committee on Animals in Research -- NEM a member 1987-88 at Yale (Box 49)
  - ALF raids, Howard U. Lab, 1982 (Box 49)
  - ALF, Morrison Lab Break-in, 1988 (Box 49)
  - Animal Research Positions [Miscellaneous], 1984 on (Box 49)
  - Animal Research vs. Animal Rights, 1983 on (Box 49)
  - Animal Research - Pro, 1985 on (Box 49)
  - Animal Research VideosSee: box 48
  - APA, Animal Research and Ethics, 1990 on (Box 49)
  - Animal Rights Groups [Names, tel. #, add., 27-p. list, dbl.-sided], etc., 1992 (Box 49)
  - Animal Rights Terrorism, 1993 (Box 49)
  - APA - CARE correspondence, 1989 on (Box 49)
  - APA Amicus brief [PAWS vs. U. of WA], 1993 (Box 49)
  - APA- CARE Committee - History and Agenda Books, 1989 on (Box 49)
  - APA - CARE Video -- Correspondence and Teacher's Guide - "Contribution and Importance. of...Animal Research...", 1996 (Box 49)
  - APA - Committee to revise animal research brochure, 1991 (Box 49)
  - APA - Science Directorate -- Merry Bullock, new Sr. Scientist, 1995 (Box 49)
  - Animal Contributions to Research by species [FBR] (Box 49)
  - Animal Models: Disease and PTSD, 1987 (Box 49)
  - Animal Research: AMA Action Plan, 1989 (Box 49)
  - Animal Research, Against, 1982 on (Box 49)
  - Animal Research, Pro [extensive, incl. Reader's Digest article], 1981 on (Box 49)
  - Animal Research: Pro and Con Debates, 1983 (Box 49)
  - Animal Research, Pro - Brochures, various (Box 49)
  - Animal rights activists - News clippings, articles, various (Box 49)
  - Animal Rights - Yale Issues, 1989 (Box 49)
  - Animal Rights - Articles, 1983 on (Box 49)
  - Animal Welfare and Use, 1982 on (Box 49)
  - Barnard, Neal (general), 1990 (Box 50)
  - Barnard, Neal vs. Michael Carey [head injury], 1993 (Box 50)
  - Behavioral Medicine, Importance of Animal Research [NEM letter to Dr. Peter Kaufman, NIH], 1990 (Box 50)
  - Budgets - Organizations that Protect Animals, 1988 (Box 50)
  - Canadians for Health Research [newsletter], 1990 on (Box 50)
  - Coons, E.E. (Ted) correspondence, 1991 on (Box 50)
  - Coons/Arronson's proposed book, 1993 (Box 50)
  - DeBakey, Dr. Michael, 1987 on (Box 50)
  - Diseases, Animal Research on: AIDS, 1988 (Box 50)
  - Diseases, Animal Research on: Arthritis, 1985 (Box 50)
  - Diseases, Animal Research on: Cancer, 1989 (Box 50)
  - Diseases, Animal Research on: Diabetes (Box 50)
  - Diseases, Animal Research on: Leukemia, 1981 (Box 50)
  - Diseases, Animal Research on: MS, 1983 (Box 50)
  - Diseases, Animal Research on: Parkinson's, 1986 on (Box 50)
  - Diseases, Animal Research on: Poliomyelitis, 1985 (Box 50)
  - Diseases, Animal Research on: Psychological, 1984 (Box 50)
  - Diseases, Animal Research on: Rabies (Box 50)
  - Diseases, Animal Research on: Stress, 1984 (Box 50)
  - Diseases, Animal Research on: T.B., 1926 (Box 50)
  - Ducks and Condors: Imprinting, 1991 (Box 50)
  - Education: APA CARE Subcomittee on - Brochures, etc., 1989 on (Box 50)
  - Education re Animal Research: Domjan, Michael, and Purdy vs. Cunningham, Gosling, 1996 on (Box 50)
  - Education, Animal, in Classroom, 1989 on (Box 50)
  - Education: Materials from Alcohol, Drug Abuse, Mental Health Administration (Box 50)
  - Education: Tactics of Antivivisectionists [NEM letter to Education Testing Service], 1992 (Box 50)
  - Ethical Issues, 1990 on (Box 50)
  - EPA Ms.: Publication of, 1992 (Box 50)
  - False Statements: Examples from Feeney, 1985 on (Box 50)
  - False Propaganda: Article submitted to American Scientist, 1995 (Box 50)
  - False Propaganda: NEM letters to Case Western, Carnegie Mellon, etc., 1989 (Box 50)
  - False Propaganda Ms: Copies of Materials supporting References [Second set] (Box 50)
  - FBR [Foundation for Biomedical Research] Update: National Opinion Survey, 1986 (Box 50)
  - FDA [Food and Drug Administration] Materials, 1984 (Box 50)
  - Federation of Behavioral, Psych. and Cognitive Sciences, 1985 on (Box 50)
  - FBR (Mary Brennan), 1995 (Box 50)
  - Field, Tiffany: Touch Research, 1992 (Box 50)
  - Frontline: [Parade Publications] - T.V. program on "Man's Best Friend", 1985 (Box 50)
  - Funding: Animal Rights Groups [from FBR], 1992 (Box 50)
  - Greenough, Wm. T. -- Correspondence, 1990 on (Box 50)
  - Gunshot Research on Dogs, 1983 (Box 50)
  - Guyton, Dr. Arthur - Correspondence re over-restrictive legislation on animal research, 1986 (Box 50)
  - Head Injury Lab, 1985 on (Box 50)
  - History of Remedy for Syphilis before Penicillin (Ehrlich) (Box 50)
  - History of Sulfa Drigs and Insulin [NEM unpublished - 3 pp.] (Box 50)
  - Horton, Larry - Analysis of Antivivisection Issues, 1989 (Box 50)
  - Hubel, David [article on fighting for animal research], 1991 (Box 50)
  - Humane Society of U.S. [Aim to abolish use of lab animals], 1993 (Box 50)
  - Humor, Animal Rights (Box 50)
  - iiFAR [incurably ill For Animal Research] (Newsletter), 1994 on (Box 50)
  - Impact [Financial, Economic] of Animal Regulations, 1989 (Box 50)
  - Importance of Animals in Biomedical Research [Department of Health and Human Services, 1993 on (Box 50)
  - IRS Returns of Animal Rights Organizations, 1987 (Box 50)
  - In Defense of Animals [animal rights organization], 1990 (Box 50)
  - Insulin, Discovery of [animal research, pro and con], 1984 (Box 50)
  - International Primate Protection League (Box 50)
  - Interview (phone) - D. Grubin Production - Trained monkey to help Susan Strong, quadraplegic, 1990 (Box 50)
  - Intro Psych Courses - Value of Basic Research, incl. on Animals, 1991 (Box 50)
  - Iproniazid [= isoniazid] [Treatment of T.B.], History of, 1957 on (Box 50)
  - Jackson Lab, 1993 (Box 50)
  - Kaufman, Stephen (Box 50)
  - King, Fred [Dir., Yerkes Primate Research Ctr.], 1986 on (Box 50)
  - Koch, Robert references [Contemporary of Pasteur, isolated T.B. bacterium], 1929 (Box 50)
  - Lab Animal Review, 1996 (Box 50)
  - Lansdell, Herbert, 1984 (Box 50)
  - McCabe, Katie [articles "Beyond Cruelty and "Who Will Live, Who Will Die?"], 1986 on (Box 50)
  - McCabe, K. [including NEM letter to Cong. Waxman on Pacheco's stand against McCabe and his own deception in Taub's lab and trials - 3/5/90], 1990 (Box 50)
  - McCabe, K. PETA's Lawsuit, 1991 (Box 50)
  - Miller, N.E. Letters re Animal Rights, 1982-83, 1982 on (Box 50)
  - Miller, N.E. - Complete set of articles on animal issues [His #221, 226, 229, 233, 238, and 251], plus NEM's article in NH Register, 2/22/89 re false statements by antivivisection, and misleading statements about NEM distributed by PETA at 1986 APA mtg., 1983 on (Box 50)
  - Miller, N.E. - Lecture at Scientists Center for Animal Welfare, 1987 (Box 50)
  - MSMR [Massachusetts Society for Medical Research] (Box 50)
  - Media Coverage, Tips on [for animal activists --1 p] (Box 50)
  - Media, Materials Supplied to Them [3-page handwritten letter by NEM to David Zimmerman of Newsday on misleading statements of antiviv.] (Box 50)
  - Medical Scientists' Legal Defense Fund [MSLDF] - Letter by Dr. Michael Goldberg] (Box 50)
  - Mishkin, Barbara [Lawyer, re proposed amendments to Animal Welfare Act, 1985 on (Box 50)
  - Mishkin, Mortimer [Fax of Scientists' Response to PCRM Document, etc.], 1990 (Box 50)
  - Mishkin, Mortimer [articles on spatial vs. object vision], 1982 on (Box 50)
  - "Misrepresentations Plague Animal Research" [Article by Charles Nicoll and Sharon Russell giving reasons to doubt Donald J. Barnes, head of Wash. office of Natl. Anti-viv. Society, and Neal Barnard of PCRM], 1992 (Box 50)
  - Misuse of Funds by Opponents of Research, 1994 (Box 50)
  - Molecular Biology and Animal Research: Downs, Alzheimers [NY Times article], 1989 (Box 50)
  - Money for Anti-Research [Fax from NBR], 1989 (Box 50)
  - "Morality and Humaneness of Animal Research on Stress and Pain" - NEM article and correspondence, 1986 (Box 50)
  - Morrison, Adrian [general], 1991 on (Box 50)
  - Morrison, Adrian - Attacked by ALF [Animal Lib Front], 1990 (Box 50)
  - Morrison, A. - American Association For the Advancement of Science Award, 1990 (Box 50)
  - Morrison, A. vs. Arluk, Arnold in Lab Animal, 1994 (Box 50)
  - Morrisoin, Adrian - Lab Break-in, 1990 on (Box 50)
  - MRMC [Medical Research Modernization Committee]: Critique of Yerkes Primate Research Center, 1995 (Box 50)
  - MRMC Reports [newsletters], 1998 on (Box 50)
  - NABR [National Association for Biomedical Research] - PR, 1985 on (Box 51)
  - NABR Alert [newsletter], 1986 on (Box 51)
  - NABR Update [newsletter], 1987 on (Box 51)
  - NAIA [National Animal Interest Alliance], 1993 (Box 51)
  - NAS [National Academy of Sciences], general animal, 1986 on (Box 51)
  - NAS Meeting, April 1989 (Box 51)
  - NAS: NEM letter to Pres. Frank Press re animal rights activists, 1990 (Box 51)
  - NAS Animal Committee, 1991 (Box 51)
  - National Charities Info Bureau [NEM letter requesting report on PETA, 1992 (Box 51)
  - NBC News: NEM letter to Dr. Bazell re animal research vs. opponents, 1990 (Box 51)
  - Need for Scientists to Become Active [Dr. Cleveland's open letter to research community] (Box 51)
  - Neuroscience Meeting '93, 1993 (Box 51)